<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ecology | Eric Marcon</title>
    <link>https://ericmarcon.github.io/en/tag/ecology/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ericmarcon.github.io/en/tag/ecology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ecology</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ericmarcon.github.io/media/icon_hu4415379d3f6fca152e373ad4be347f7a_5538_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Ecology</title>
      <link>https://ericmarcon.github.io/en/tag/ecology/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Species Abundance Distributions</title>
      <link>https://ericmarcon.github.io/en/course/distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ericmarcon.github.io/en/course/distributions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No other general attribute of ecological communities besides species richness has commanded more theoretical and empirical attention than relative species abundance (Hubbell, 2001).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of the course is to understand the main abundance distributions, master the different representations and understand area-species relationships, at different scales.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measurement of Biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://ericmarcon.github.io/en/course/biodiversity-eft/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ericmarcon.github.io/en/course/biodiversity-eft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The original definition of biodiversity is the number of species in a community. It has been extended in many ways, often using ad-hoc indices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course introduces a unified approach to measuring biodiversity, based on information theory, which allows biodiversity to be described as an effective number of categories (usually species) corresponding to the question at hand: taxonomic diversity when all species are considered equivalent, phylogenetic diversity when their evolutionary proximity is taken into account, and functional diversity when the distance between pairs of species does not fit into a tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The measures presented are decomposable at different scales (α, β and γ diversity) and can be estimated from incomplete data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://ericmarcon.github.io/en/course/dynamique-ft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ericmarcon.github.io/en/course/dynamique-ft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This course is dedicated to the students of the joint Master&amp;rsquo;s program &lt;a href=&#34;https://globalforestry.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Global Forestry&lt;/a&gt;.
It is an introduction to the dynamics of tropical forests. The objectives are to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be able to describe the state and dynamics of a forest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the dynamics of succession and the role of disturbances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand some fundamental theories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce anthropogenic disturbances before looking at forest management and harvesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
